

# **Paschall Davis**

## Software Engineer







As an engineer with a proven record of technical skills, strong principles, leadership, and team focus through my seven years working in technology, I'm searching for roles where I can collaborate with highly motivated likeminded developers as we strive to continue learning and deliver excellent software. I thrive in environments with enough structure to provide stability, while still having enough flexibility for occasional explorations into optimizations and new technology.

Contact me

Download my resume

# **Education**

### **Yale University**

## Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering • 2014

- Two-time varsity swim team letter earner
- Top 8 finisher in the 100 yard freestyle at 2013 Ivy Championship Meet Swim team treasurer and volunteer assistant coach 2013-14 season

## **Skills**

#### Languages

Java (primary), Python (some experience)

#### **Technologies** Kubernetes, Helm, Docker, Postgresql, Spring Boot, Git, AWS, ArgoCD, Terraform, Axon

Framework, Kafka, SonarQube, Quarkus

#### Continuous Integration and Delivery, Extreme Programming, Test Driven Development,

**Development Practices** 

Pair Programming

#### Certifications AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (April 2020)

# MoneyLion

**Experience** 

### Lead Backend Engineer • Jan 2020 — Present • Recognized as leader and top performer by three promotions to Senior, Team

## Lead, and Lead Engineer levels

- Rewrote Checking Account product using Spring Boot and Axon Framework to integrate with new banking provider and achieve higher levels of scalability and customer satisfaction
- Identified opportunity for optimizations on premium "turbo" transactions and swiftly implemented them to protect customers from a confusing user experience • Led initiative to track code quality and test coverage with SonarQube, resulting in an increase of test coverage from ~25% to >80% across all services and a buy-in
- from all developers to write tests • Designed a serverless architecture for an integration with Plaid to save money and deliver higher availability while maintaining developer experience
- Developed a set of shared libraries to ensure that the code within the libraries can be tested, packaged, and consumed independently across the Banking team's

• Introduced a pattern for blameless retrospective meetings on my team before

sharing the structure with the greater engineering organization

many microservices **Royal Bank of Canada** 

#### automating infrastructure and security within RBC • Managed Jenkins CI/CD pipeline to test and deploy to container orchestration

## platform in an efficient and scalable manner

Software Engineer • Mar 2018 — Jan 2020

 Expanded client on-boarding and incident management process to enable platform consumer growth to over 50 internal teams Assisted with implementation and support of Databases as a Service project to

Built and supported a system of ~25 Spring Boot Java microservices for

- provide MariaDB run on Kubernetes to developer teams Led team retrospective and weekly Kanban project grooming meetings
- **Innovid**

#### Junior to Senior level • Resolved complex client issues related to ad serving on publisher websites and

Sr. Tier 2 Technical Support Engineer • May 2015 — Feb 2018

proprietary application defects • Trained and advised junior teammates throughout support ticket process and led

initiative to introduce Knowledge Centered Support practices across the team

• Repeatedly recognized as a leader and top performer with two promotions from

• Developed custom MySQL reports to fulfill client requests and provide data to the internal Analytics team

• Effectively communicated and collaborated with colleagues and clients with

various levels of technical backgrounds to manage critical projects

- **Outside Interests** 
  - Music League of Legends esports

Running

 Fantasy novels Cooking

Mixology

Made by Paschall Davis with help from jglovier's **Jekyll resume template**.